(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
wonderland
Lyrics・Composition：堀込高由紀
Lyrics・Composition: Takayuki Horikome
#INAinaNeverland
迷い込んだ森にある本当
The truth that lies in the forest I've wandered into
探しに行く月の光
I'm going to search for the moonlight
羊歯を踏んで足を濡らして
Stepping on ferns, getting my feet wet
ヒトリホトリ夏の小径
Alone by the shore on a summer path
よく笑って泣いて見つめ合って
Laughing, crying, and gazing at each other
恐る恐る恋に落ちた
Fearfully, we fell in love
二人歩き出した違う方へ
We both started walking in different directions
呼び合う声だけ　もどかしく
Frustratingly, only our voices calling to each other
Find me in the wonderland
そろそろ手を汚して
It's about time you got your hands dirty
自分の欲しいものは
The things that you want for yourself
追いかけてみる　三つ編みをほどいて
Try chasing them, undoing your braids
同じ星をかじる
We bite into the same star
二人きり　寂しかった夜になって
Just the two of us, as the night becomes lonely
また明るい夢のほとり
Again by the shore of a bright dream
問いかけで残した心だって
Even the heart left behind with a question
ここから始まる歌になる
Will become a song that starts from here
世界は君に
The world belongs to you
世界は君のものさ
The world is yours
どこへ行こうか
Where shall we go?
あなたは笑う
You smile
踏み外してみようか
Shall we try taking a wrong step?
後ろめたさが
The guilt
私を誘う
Invites me
Finally in your wonderland
どうしたって生まれ変わる
No matter what, I'll be reborn
ほとばしる強い意志が
A surging strong will
偽らば慎重な命だった
If it were a lie, it was a cautious life
私だけじゃ道は
With just me, the path is...
いつからか星を数え繋ぎ合わせ
Since when did I start counting and connecting stars?
また知らない夏の星座
The summer constellations I still don't know
見つめ合って泣いて朝になって
Staring at each other, crying, and then morning comes
ここから始まる物語
The story starts from here
もう一人じゃないのよ
I'm not alone anymore
夢のようでしょ
It's like a dream, right?
私は歌う
I sing
寂しさは色を変え
Loneliness changes color
旗の下へと
To the base of the flag
二人は集う
The two gather
何も思い通りにならないことが
The fact that nothing goes as planned
始まったから
Has begun
踏み外してみようか
Shall we try taking a wrong step?
目隠しを解いて
Removing the blindfold
手の鳴る方へ
To the sound of clapping hands
In your wonderland
あなたが迷う場所に
In the place where you wander
明かりを灯すために
To light a lamp
あなたが一つ叩いて
You clap once
麗しく笑いましょう
Let's laugh beautifully
もう一人じゃないのよ
I'm not alone anymore
とても怖いでしょ幸せなんて
Happiness is very scary, isn't it?
寂しさは色を変え
Loneliness changes color
旗の下へと
To the base of the flag
二人は集う
The two gather
世界は君のものさ
The world is yours
手を叩いて
Clap your hands
あなたがいて
With you here
踏み外してみようか
Shall we try taking a wrong step?
愛する人が
The person I love
私を誘う
Invites me
Finally in your wonderland
In your wonderland
綺麗な吐息になって
Becoming a beautiful breath
あなたの歌を歌って
Singing your song
delete
優しい言葉を失くした
Lost the kind words
闇の中
Inside the darkness
最後の祈りも
Even the final prayer
静かに消えてった
Quietly faded away
夜明けは遠く 君は独りで
Dawn is far away, and you are alone
出口のない夢の中で
Inside a dream with no exit
涙だけが道を照らした
Only tears lit the way
誰にも届かず
Reaching no one
朽ちてゆく歌がある
There is a song that rots away
悲しみ一つも
Not even a single sadness
叶えられずに終わる
Ends without being fulfilled
声もなく君はただ泣いた
Without a voice, you just cried
delete
ノイズが解けて　時は満ちて
The noise dissolves, the time is ripe
遠くが霞む　風も
The distance grows hazy, and the wind
数を増した
has increased in strength
光をもたらす
Bringing light
定めの日は来ない
The day of destiny will not come
淀んだ時間は
Stagnant time is
まだらに凍りついて
patchy and frozen
恐れを説いた　宵闇を手に
Holding the twilight that preached fear
抱きしめ合う　形をして
Taking the shape of holding each other
君と僕は　傷を重ねた
You and I overlapped our wounds
どこにも届かず
Reaching nowhere
君の声は潰えた
Your voice has perished
消えゆくことさえ
Even the fact it's fading away
誰も気付かぬままに
Without anyone noticing
無造作に土を増やした
Casually added to the earth
いつか光の中で
One day, in the light
そばにいてくれると信じて
Believing that you'll be by my side
形のない
Formless
僕たちは形のある
We, into a world with form
世界へといつか帰る
will return one day
道を捜した
We searched for the path
忘れてしまった
Having forgotten
優しい人の声を捜して
Searching for the voice of a kind person
彷徨う道はどこまで遠い
How far the wandering path goes
声もなく君はただ泣いた
Without a voice, you just cried
道はやがて途絶えた
The path eventually came to an end
Waa!
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
おはよう、こんにちは、こんばんは！
Welcome to my birthday live!
Yay! It's finally happening!
Thank you guys for being so patient.
I know this was originally planned for around May, around my birthday,
but it's finally happening in December!
Thank you so much everyone for being patient and supporting me so this could happen.
Thank you so, so much staff-san for all your hard work.
I'm so happy and I'm so nervous, can you tell?
So, did you guys enjoy the first two songs?
Wonderland and delete.
Wonderland is milet-san's song.
It's not Ina's live without a milet song.
I don't think it's as well known, but it's definitely one of my favorite songs by her,
so I wanted to perform it for you guys someday.
And delete, it's actually an insert song in the
Sword Art Online movie, Ordinal Scale.
And I really liked the song in the movie and I, you know, I wanted to perform it for you guys.
Coincidentally too, they're both composed by Yuki Kajiura-san,
which I'm a really big fan of because she has
a magical sense for creating these mysterious...
...yet mythical, mythical songs.
Yeah!
And as you can see, we're kind of in a monochrome world.
You'd be like, "Hey, did they forget to add in the colors
to this place? What's happening?"
But you know, I... it's intended.
I've always said before that before I joined Hololive and all,
the world kind of looked bland and monochrome.
But as time went on here, where I met all wonderful members,
wonderful staff, and it became a lot more colorful.
So I wanted to kind of add that into this special live.
My first birthday live!
So yeah, maybe you know, if we go down this live,
we'll find some color again?
And of course, I've got to mention the title of the live:
Neverland Paradox.
It sounds very difficult, but if you break it down,
Neverland is kind of this imaginary, ideal world
that's not supposed to exist.
But if it doesn't exist, why do we know about it?
Why? How? It's a paradox.
So, you know, kind of like that.
Let's pretend that this world here, right here, is Neverland,
and we'll go down this journey together.
Yeah, together!
Anyways, if you want to talk about this live somewhere,
let me see the comments later too, #INAinaNeverland.
#INAinaNeverland. Is it here? Is it here? Is it here? Somewhere?
So tweet about it! Tell your friends! It's happening!
Ina's first birthday live! Yay!
Anyways, I hope you'll have a lot of fun during the live.
Let's enjoy our trip through Neverland together.
Never-ever-land.
Never-ever-neverland.
Never-ever-never-ever-ever-neverland.
Yeah! Let's go!
ダミーダミー
Lyrics:Composition: DECO*27
Dummy Dummy
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
一人じゃできないこと　探してみたよ
I searched for things that couldn't be done alone.
二人じゃなきゃできない何かを
Something that can only be done by two.
でもその答えを探せば探すほど
But the more I search for that answer,
誰かと笑ってる僕を殺したくなる
The more I want to kill the "me"
who's laughing with someone.
1 + 1 が一番美しいよ
1 + 1 is the most beautiful.
僕はそう思いたくて誰かに縛られてる
I wanted to believe that, and I'm bound by someone.
解きたくてそんな自分が一番美しいと思った
Wanting to break free,
I thought that version of myself was the most beautiful.
二人でできないこと　たくさんある
There are many things that can't be done by two.
一人でできることが　多すぎて
There are too many things that can be done alone.
だから僕がもっと大量に必要だよ
That's why I need much more of "me".
そして誰かに僕の役を押し付けた
And then I thrust my role upon someone else.
僕の声は　一言も　輪になれない
My voice can't join the circle by even a word.
なれないんだから
Because it just can't.
ここで誰かが演じる僕を見てるよ
Here, I'm watching someone perform as me.
僕はそう思いたくて誰かが演じる僕が
I wanted to believe that,
because the me performed by someone else
僕のそれより美しくて輝いているから
Is more beautiful and radiant than the real me.
僕によく似たあなたに僕をプレゼントするよ
I'll present myself to you, who looks just like me.
要らなくなったらそっとゴミに包んで捨てて
If you don't need me anymore,
just wrap me in trash and throw me away.
要らなくなったらゴミに包んで捨てれるよ
If you don't need me anymore,
you can just wrap me in trash and throw me away.
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee.
Lyrics: 鳥居羊 / Composition: うたたP
Lyrics: Torii Hitsuji / Composition: Utata-P
飛ばして みんなが幸せなの
Soar away, everyone is happy
この世界のこと
About this world
聞きたいって 知りたいって
I want to hear, I want to know
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を澄ませて
In the park by the water, everyone listens closely
ワクワクするね ねえ、オンディーヌ
It's exciting, isn't it, Ondine?
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
さあさあ、皆さん 教えてあげます
Now then, everyone, I'll tell you
皆が気になっていること
What everyone is curious about
疑問に思っていること 全部教えてあげます
What everyone is wondering, I'll tell you all
えー、皆さんが幸福なのは義務なんです
Well, it is your duty to be happy
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It is your duty.
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々幸福安心委員会は
We, the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee,
皆様の幸せを願い そして 支えます
Wish for and support everyone's happiness
幸福なのは義務なんです 幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy, it is your duty to be happy
幸福なのは義務なんです 幸せですか？ 義務ですよ
It is your duty to be happy, are you happy? It is your duty.
ですから 安心してお任せなさいね
So, please leave it to us with peace of mind
皆様の幸せが 我々の幸せ
Everyone's happiness is our happiness
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ
Are you happy? It is your duty.
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら...
If you are not happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電撃 火あぶり 究明
Hanging, beheading, shooting, boiling, drowning, electrocution, burning, investigation
埋殺 薬殺 石打ち 鋸 磔
Burying alive, lethal injection, stoning, sawing, crucifixion
好きなのを選んでね
Please choose whichever you like
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
さあさあ、皆さん 幸せだけにしてます
Now then, everyone, I'm making you only happy
不安とかも 何も無いでしょう？
You don't have any anxiety or anything, right?
怖い...
I'm scared...
怖いわ...
幸せすぎて 怖いわ
I'm so happy, I'm scared
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
さあさあ、皆さん 死にました
Now then, everyone, they died
王様に背いた者は 死にました
Those who defied the King died
葬儀に出るなら 向こうに並べ
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there
それ以外は 幸せに暮らせ
Otherwise, live happily
以上！ 幸福なのは義務なんです
That is all! It is your duty to be happy
義務なんです 義務ですよ 義務なんです
It is your duty, it is your duty, it is your duty
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy
義務なんです 義務ですよ 義務なんです
It is your duty, it is your duty, it is your duty
幸せじゃないなら...
If you are not happy...
死ね
Die.
名前のない怪物
Lyrics・Composition：ryo(supercell)
Nameless Monster
震えてるわ
You're trembling
澄みきった瞳
With clear eyes
レンガの病棟で
In the brick hospital ward
うまく歌えなくて
Unable to sing well
霧が煙る夜
On a foggy night
浮かべ合った月
The moon we floated together
ほら見て私を
Look at me
目を逸らさないで
Don't look away
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Inside the black iron bars
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born
悪意の代償を願う
Wishing for the price of malice
がままにお前に
As it is, for you
さあ喰らえ正義を
Now, consume justice
壊して　壊される前に
Destroy it, before you are destroyed
因果の代償を払い
Paying the price of karma
共にゆこう　名前のない怪物
Let's go together, nameless monster
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing
突如もう五月蝿くて
Suddenly, it's so loud
思い出せないの
I can't remember
あの日の旋律
That day's melody
雨はまだ止まない
The rain still won't stop
何も見えないの
I can't see anything
ほら見てこんなに
Look, I've...
大きくなったの
...grown this much
黒い雨降らすこの空
This sky that rains black rain
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis
愛した傍観者たちに
To the bystanders I loved
さあ今奮え正義を
Now, stir up justice
消せない傷跡抱きしめて
Embracing the indelible scars
この身体受け入れ共にゆこう
Accepting this body, let's go together
名前のない怪物
Nameless monster
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Inside the black iron bars
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born
悪意の代償を願う
Wishing for the price of malice
がままにお前に
As it is, for you
さあ喰らえ正義を
Now, consume justice
壊して　壊される前に
Destroy it, before you are destroyed
因果の代償を払い
Paying the price of karma
報いよ名もなき怪物
Repay it, nameless monster
黒い雨降らすこの空
This sky that rains black rain
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis
愛した傍観者たちに
To the bystanders I loved
さあ今奮え正義を
Now, stir up justice
消せない傷跡抱きしめて
Embracing the indelible scars
この身体受け入れ共にゆこう
Accepting this body, let's go together
名前のない怪物
Nameless monster
The Nameless Monster
悲しみは笑います
Sadness laughs
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？
Shall We Dance?
生きてるマリオネット
A living marionette
支援者がスイングしたら
When the supporters swing
さあ、お祝いはいかが
Now, how about a celebration?
Odd-to-too, odd-to-too, odd-to-too...
私上手く踊れないわ
I can't dance very well
痛みも憂いも悲しみは
Pain, grief, and sadness
混ぜて、止めて
Mix them, stop them
おやすみのキス
A goodnight kiss
Shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望、欲望 This is the life
Despair, desire, this is the life
Shadow line 余計なこと
Shadow line, unnecessary things
考えないで一つになりましょう
Don't think about them, let's become one
いいな、いいな
How nice, how nice
人間って、人間って
To be human, to be human
いいな
It's nice
泣きたいのに笑っちゃう
Even though I want to cry, I laugh
人生って、見える
Life is visible
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true heart
笑うフリ忘れるの
Forgetting how to pretend to laugh
Odd-to-too, odd-to-too, odd-to-too...
私上手く生きれないわ
I can't live very well
本音も嘘も不安も
True feelings, lies, and anxiety
溶かして、蓋して
Melt them, cover them
おやすみなさい
Good night
Shall we dream? 夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
泣き出し、目覚めて This is the life
Bursting into tears, waking up, this is the life
Shadow line 目を閉じて
Shadow line, close your eyes
嫌なこと全部全部忘れましょう
Let's forget all the bad things
Shall we dance? 不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if we're clumsy
間違えてもいいよ This is the life
It's okay to make mistakes, this is the life
Shadow step 余計なこと
Shadow step, unnecessary things
考えないでステップを踏み出せ
Don't think about them, take a step forward
Shall we smile? 今だけは
Shall we smile? Just for now
一緒に笑ってみませんか？
Won't you try laughing with me?
Shadow dance 今だけは
Shadow dance, just for now
全部忘れて一緒に飛びましょう
Forget everything and let's jump together
Shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望、欲望 This is the life
Despair, desire, this is the life
Shadow line 余計なこと
Shadow line, unnecessary things
考えないで一つになりましょう
Don't think about them, let's become one
いいな、いいな
How nice, how nice
人間って、いいな
To be human is nice
いいな、いいな
How nice, how nice
人間って、人間って
To be human, to be human
いいな
It's nice
WAH BAR
VIOLET
Lyrics: LUMINA Composition: seibin
運ばれてる夜の　目に映った星
Stars reflected in the eyes of the night being carried along
ひな向月が　味を擽る
The fledgling moon tickles the taste
流れる光に　沿って歩いてみたら
If I try walking along the flowing light
耳に囁いた　君に届くかな
I wonder if my whisper will reach you
今手を繋いでも
Even if we hold hands now
精一杯抱きしめても
Even if I hug you with all my might
空は秋に満ちるんだ
The sky will be filled with autumn
指先でゆらゆらと
Swaying with my fingertips
その五線譜が
That musical staff
止まった時計の　針に踏み込んだ
Stepped onto the hands of the stopped clock
たった待った願いさえ
Even the wish I just waited for
離れた今は
Now that it's far away
その笑顔を　知ってるよ
I know that smile
瞬歌う夜の　目に映った空
The sky reflected in the eyes of the night singing light
爽やかな香り　鼻を擽る
A refreshing scent tickles my nose
足跡を合わせて　歩いてみたら
If I try walking matching my footsteps
私を見ていた　君に届くかな
I wonder if it will reach you who was looking at me
ずっと手を繋いでも
Even if we hold hands forever
瞳をみつめてみても
Even if I gaze into your eyes
空は雨に染まるんだ
The sky will be dyed in rain
君を呼び出した声
The voice that called out to you
の形が
The shape of...
渇いた笑顔を　濡らして
Drenching the parched smile
強く叫んだ声が
The voice that shouted strongly
重なった今は
Now that they've overlapped
その言葉を　知ってるよ
I know those words
君は分かってるかな
I wonder if you understand
教えてくれた
You taught me
戻らない
Not returning
その幸せは
That happiness is...
運ばれてる夜の　目に映った星
Stars reflected in the eyes of the night being carried along
光った月が　消えてゆく
The shining moon fades away
指先でゆらゆらと
Swaying with my fingertips
その動きが
That movement...
止まった時計の　針に踏み込んだ
Stepped onto the hands of the stopped clock
雲が描いた列車
The train drawn by the clouds
強く噛み
Biting strongly...
その笑顔を　知ってるよ
I know that smile
Hi, welcome back!
Ah, that was quite a lot of songs.
And look! We got some color back.
What color is this? Violet?
Well, I hope you guys enjoyed the songs.
We sang a couple of songs.
First one being "DUMMY DUMMY" by DECO*27.
皆さん、
Everyone,
It's a song I've been fond of for quite a long time actually.
It's, uh... I think it's lesser known than some of his really, you know, famous songs...
...but it has a special place in my heart.
So I really wanted to sing it for you guys.
And I hope you guys enjoyed it.
The song I sang after that is called "こちら、幸福安心委員会です。"
The song I sang after that is called "This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee."
I think it's a really fun song that's perfect for a cult.
Although I wouldn't know anything about being a cult.
Definitely not a cult, by the way.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ！
Are you happy? It's a duty!
Yeah, and the song after that was "名前のない怪物".
Yeah, and the song after that was "The Nameless Monster."
If you guys know, I really love EGOIST...
...and one of my favorite songs by them is actually this song.
I've sung it, I think, once or twice in karaoke before...
...but I really wanted to sing it in a live as well, so I hope you guys enjoyed it.
The song after that was called "Shall We Dance" by ReoNa.
A song that you guys actually, a lot of you asked me to sing it after "Nai Nai"...
...because it's also from the same series, anime series "Shadow House".
But since, you know, the title itself is "Shall We Dance" and it's a very danceable song...
...I thought I might as well save it for the live, which I hope you guys enjoyed.
I think the choreo was a little difficult for me to learn...
...but I think I pulled it off. Did I, did I do okay?
Yes, and the song after that is "Violet", my first original song.
It's very nostalgic to me every time I listen to it.
And I guess it's been quite a while since I first released it.
As it was my first original song, I learned a lot from it...
...and so it's really special to me.
But as I've said before, it's been a while since the first original.
So maybe it's time for a second one? Sometime soon.
Soon? Soon.
But anyways, thank you everyone for always supporting me.
Thanks everyone who helped in making this live happen.
Without you guys, staff-san, everyone, this wouldn't have happened.
So thank you very, very much.
Yeah, I guess we'll move on to the next song.
I hope you'll enjoy it.
Meconopsis
Lyrics: WUNDER RIKU Composition・Arrangement: M2U
Sapphire petals fall through infinite white sea
Misty whispers call, drowning in endless dreams
Is this my sanity, clinging for my memory?
Is this humanity, or long forgotten land?
壇上の野草が最後のはなびらを落とす
Wild grass on the stage drops its final petal
心はあなたの嘘をすべて暴く
My heart exposes all of your lies
Enough! No, I will keep playing endlessly
A world without love is not the world that I want to see
If such a man withers, I'll oh yes see
Tell me how do I reconcile the joy in my memory
今だ身を落とす最後のチャンス
Now is the last chance to throw myself down
血の誓い 藍の誓い
A blood oath, an indigo oath
Together we may die, love is now and forever
孤独に割れぬ愛を...
A love that cannot be broken in solitude...
When the silver diamond oceans alight, eternity sapphire petals fall through
壇上の野草が最後のはなびらを落とす
Wild grass on the stage drops its final petal
心はあなたの嘘をすべて暴く
My heart exposes all of your lies
Enough! No, I will keep playing endlessly
A world without love is not the world that I want to see
a world that I want to see
If sentiment fritters
our way to see
Tell me how
do I reconcile
the tour in my memory
今がみんなを映し出す最後の一手
Now is the final move that projects everyone
And dreams fell off
in the arms of love
Enough!
In love!
Though I will keep praying endlessly
A world without love is not the world
that I want to see
If sentiment fritters
our way to see
Tell me how
do I reconcile
the tour in my memory
今がみんなを映し出す最後の一手
Now is the final move that projects everyone
血の誓い
Blood oath
愛の誓い
Oath of love
Till death may die
Love is now and for forever
ああ、いつものように
Ah, just like always
過ぎる日々に欠伸が出る
I yawn at the passing days
さんざめく夜、越え、
Crossing the bustling night,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
Morning falls upon the city of Shibuya
どこか虚しいような
A feeling like something is empty,
そんな気持ち
Such a feeling
つまらないな、でもそれでいい
It's boring, but that's okay
そんなもんさ、これでいい
That's just how it is, this is fine
知らず知らず隠してた
The true voice I've been hiding unconsciously
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let it ring out, look
見ないフリしていても
Even if I pretend not to see
確かにそこに、ある
It's definitely right there
ああ、感じたままに描く
Ah, I paint it as I feel it
自分で選んだその色で
With the colors that I chose myself
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning wrapped in sleepy air
訪れた青い世界
A blue world has arrived
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying I like the things I like
怖くて仕方ないけれど
I'm so scared I can't help it, but
本当の自分に出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I was able to meet my true self
ああ、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
Ah, the more I reach out my hand
遠くへゆく
The further away it goes
思うようにいかない今日も
Even today, when things don't go as planned
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I'm struggling hectically again
悔しい気持ちもただ情けなくて
Even the frustrating feelings are just miserable
涙が出る
And the tears fall
踏み込むほど苦しくなる
The further I step in, the more painful it becomes
痛くもなる
It starts to hurt too
ああ、感じたままに進む
Ah, I move forward as I feel it
自分で選んだこの道を
Along this path that I chose myself
重いまぶた擦る夜に
In the night when I rub my heavy eyelids
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung to the blue oath
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
It's not just about 'having fun'
本当にできる？不安になるけど
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but
何回でも、ほら何回でも
As many times as it takes, look, as many times as it takes
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I've been painting because I lack confidence
何回でも、ほら何回でも
As many times as it takes, look, as many times as it takes
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
What I've built up will become my weapon
周りを見たって、誰かと比べたって
Even if I look around, even if I compare myself to others
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
What is the one thing only I can do?
今でも自信なんかない、それでも
I still don't have any confidence, but even so
感じたことない気持ち
A feeling I've never felt before
知らずにいた想い
Thoughts I never knew I had
あの日踏み出して、初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
Stepping out that day, all this pain I felt for the first time too
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing the things I love
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a light that is still small
大丈夫、行こう、あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go, the rest is just to enjoy it
ああ、全てを掛けて描く
Ah, I paint with everything I've got
自分にしか出せない色で
With colors that only I can produce
朝も夜も走り続け
Running through both morning and night
見つけ出した青い光
The blue light that I found
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing the things I love
良いことだけを
Only the good things
思い回る
revolve in my mind
あの日の透明な僕じゃない
I'm not the transparent me of that day
ありのままの
Just as I am
かけがえの無い僕だ
I'm the irreplaceable me
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hidden
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
let your true voice ring out, look
見ないふりしていても
Even if you're pretending not to see
確かにそこに今もそこにあるよ
It's certainly there, even now it's there
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hidden
本当の声を響かせてよ、さあ
let your true voice ring out, come on
見ないふりしていても
Even if you're pretending not to see
確かにそこに君の中に
It's certainly there, within you
Come back Takodachi, come here.
Sit, sit.
How was the live? Did you enjoy it?
How was it? Fun?
I'm glad, I'm glad.
Thanks always for your support.
Without you, this wouldn't have happened.
Wow, it's been a long three years, huh?
Well, let's continue to have more fun
from now on too, okay?
Yeah?
Forever, ever, ever, ever, ever.
Thanks for watching!!
It took a while, but we did it!!!
Thank you, always, for your support.
And for your patience in waiting for this live!!
I hope you enjoyed it!!! Thank you also to all
the staff and everyone who helped make this happen!
I'll keep doing my best!! WAH!!!!
2023.05.20 Ninomae Ina'nis